A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Vice President, Office Files of Mary E. McClymont FA594
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Vice President, Office Files of Mary E. McClymont
Bulk, 1981-2008 1969-2008
bulk
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA594
7.6 Cubic Feet
Ms. McClymont started as a Program Officer with the Foundation’s Human Rights and Governance Program in April of 1988. She was made Deputy Director of the Rights and Social Justice Program in October of 1993. After serving as Acting Director from August 1995 to May of 1996, she was subsequently promoted to Senior Director of the Rights and Social Justice program, later Peace and Social Justice. While at the Ford Foundation, Ms. McClymont led a team of researchers who documented NGO law-related strategies to advance human rights globally. This work resulted in the publication of Many Roads to Justice: The Law-Related Work of Ford Foundation Grantees Around the World (2000). She left the Foundation in 2000, but returned from 2006 to 2008 to serve as Vice President of the program. The office files of Mary E. McClymont span from 1969 to 2008, with the bulk of the records date from 1981 to 2008. The files contain extensive information about the Global Law Programs Learning Initiative (GLPLI). The Initiative documented and studied the Foundation’s work in promoting legal reform, public interest law and access to justice from 1998 to 2001. Another project heavily documented in the collection is the Comparative Constitutionalism Project. Other files pertain to grantees or Foundation policy. The files related to the Learning Enhancements Fund are particularly illustrative in regards to Foundation policy. They document the internal Foundation process behind how grant assessments were made, and include a practical guide for program staff files.
(19 Hollinger document boxes)
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment. Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Organizational History
When Susan Berresford became President of the Foundation in 1996, she established a new program structure consisting of three large thematic programs. Peace and Social Justice (PSJ) was one of these three programs. Its overall mission was to help improve government performance and accountability, foster a thriving independent civil society, and promote human rights. It was comprised of two global units: Governance and Civil Society, and Human Rights. In 2009, Peace and Social Justice became the Democracy, Rights and Justice Program.
Biographical Note
Mary E. McClymont received a B.A. from the University of Nebraska at Lincoln in 1971, a J.D. from Georgetown University Law Center in 1976, and an LL.M. in International Legal Studies from American University's Washington College of Law in 1987.
Ms. McClymont started as a Program Officer with the Foundation’s Human Rights and Governance Program in April of 1988. She was made Deputy Director of the Rights and Social Justice Program in October of 1993. After serving as Acting Director from August 1995 to May of 1996, she was subsequently promoted to Senior Director of the Rights and Social Justice program. In October 1996, Rights and Social Justice became Peace and Social Justice.
While at the Ford Foundation, Ms. McClymont led a team of researchers who documented NGO law-related strategies to advance human rights globally. This work resulted in the publication of Many Roads to Justice: The Law-Related Work of Ford Foundation Grantees Around the World (2000). She left the Foundation in December of 2000, but returned from 2006 to 2008 to serve as the Vice President of Peace and Social Justice. After leaving, she was appointed Executive Director of Global Rights, a human rights organization. As of 2011 she is President of the Public Welfare Foundation.
Arrangement
Arranged into 3 series.
Scope and Contents Note
The office files of Mary E. McClymont span from 1969 to 2008, with the bulk of the records date from 1981 to 2008. The files contain extensive information about the Global Law Programs Learning Initiative (GLPLI). The Initiative studied and documented the Foundation’s work in the legal field to promote legal reform, public interest law and access to justice from 1998 to 2001. According to a 1998 memorandum, the purpose of the project was to review past and current Foundation grants in order to guide future programming. The end result was the book, Many Roads to Justice. The book was translated into several languages and distributed to nonprofit organizations around the globe.
The collection also contains information about the Comparative Constitutionalism Project. Developed and administered by the Governance unit of Peace and Social Justice, the project studied alternative political arrangements for promoting pluralism in diverse societies. Constitutionalism in Africa (1999-2000) was a focus, as the Foundation’s goal was to encourage ethnic harmony without forcing homogenization on autonomous cultures and communities.
Other files pertain to grantees or Foundation policy. The files related to the Learning Enhancements Fund are particularly illustrative in regards to Foundation policy. They document the internal Foundation process behind how grant assessments were made, and include a practical guide for program staff files.
Related Collections
FA674 Ford Foundation records, Peace and Social Justice (PSJ), Office Files of Mary McClymont, 1984-1990.
Separated Materials
Appendix A: Reports – Unpublished reports written by Ford Foundation staff and consultants were removed from their original folders, scanned and transferred to the Archives' collection of staff and consultant reports. See Appendix A for a list of these reports and their specific assigned number. The reports are listed in alphabetical order by author. The assigned number may be used to access reports in the online catalog.
Conditions Governing Access note
Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research.
Date spans of this collection range from 1969-2008. As such, some of the material is closed to scholarly access until the applicable records are more than ten years old. Material will be open for research as records reach the ten year threshold, 2015-2019.
Select individual files are restricted, as noted. Permission to access these files must be obtained from the Ford Foundation before scholarly access is permitted.
Ford Foundation
- Board of Trustees, 1996-1999; I
  Scope and Contents
  These files contain dockets for meetings of the Board of Trustees. Several of the files also contain handwritten notes, memoranda or discussion papers relating to meetings of the Board or the Board’s Audit and Management Committee.
  - Meeting -- Memoranda Re: Development Finance Institutions, Schedule, Discussion Papers, Notes, Background (1 o 2), Dec 11-12, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Meeting -- Docket (2 of 2), Dec 11-12, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Meeting -- Docket, Mar 10, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Meeting -- Docket, Schedule, Discussion Paper, Budgets (1 of 2), Jun 25-26, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Meeting -- Docket (2 of 2), Jun 25-26, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Meeting -- Presentation, Docket (1 of 2), Sep 24-26, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Meeting -- Docket (2 of 2), Sep 24-26, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Meeting -- Docket, Schedule, Reference Memos, Jan 28-29, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Meeting -- Docket, Discussion Papers, May 28, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Meeting -- Docket, Memoranda Re: Meeting Agenda, Sep 23, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Meeting -- Schedule, Recommendation Memo, Budget Information (1 of 2), May 27, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Meeting -- Docket Parts I and II, List of Grant Actions (2 of 2), May 27, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Meeting -- Audit and Management Committee -- Memoranda Re: Agenda, Discussion Paper on Philippines, Background (1 of 2), Sep 30, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Meeting -- Audit and Management Committee -- Docket (2 of 2), Sep 30, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Subject Files, 1981-2008; II
  Conditions Governing Access
  Date spans of this series range from 1981-2008. As such, some of the material is closed to scholarly access until the applicable records are more than ten years old. Material will be open for research as records reach the ten year threshold, 2015-2019.
  Ms. McClymont kept subject files on grantees and grant projects, Ford Foundation policy, and areas where Foundation policy directly impacted grant projects, such as Foundation support for affirmative action.
  Arrangement
  Alphabetically arranged.
  - Affirmative Action -- FF Support for Affirmative Action, Background, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    File is closed to scholarly research.
    Date Restricted Material -- Contains records less than 10 years old -- Restricted records are Open to scholarly research in 2018.
  - Africa Human Rights Meeting -- Memoranda Re: Refugees, Correspondence, Notes, Report, May 1997 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - American Bar Association World Justice Project -- Correspondence, Notes, Project Information, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Articles on Foundations and Conservatism, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Articles on Globalization (with notes), 1998 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Atlantic Philanthropies Meeting -- Notes, Memoranda, Correspondence, and Background on Anti-Terrorism and Human Rights Grants, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Berresford, Susan -- Speeches, Articles, 1996-1998 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Berresford, Susan -- Transition Plans -- Memoranda, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Biennial Representatives and Directors Meeting -- Notes, Meeting Book, Feb 24-28, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Budget and Financial Analysis Network (BFAN) Learning Group -- Memoranda and Correspondence Re: Public Budgeting as a Grant Making Area, Dec 10, 1999-Aug 11, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Center for the Advancement of Women -- Correspondence, Notes, Reports and Background on Grants, 2006-2007 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Central American Initiative Grantee Meeting -- Background, Memoranda, etc., 1996 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - China -- Judicial Reform Feedback Proposal -- Memoranda Re: Observers Group Evaluations, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - China -- Legal Education and Research, Jul 1987 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Civil Society Research Project -- Concept Paper, Correspondence Re: Project, Notes, etc., Jul 9, 1997-Mar 24, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Collaborative Community Organizing Evaluation -- Correspondence, Memoranda, Background, 2000-2001 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Comparative Constitutionalism Project -- Working Papers (1 of 7), 1990 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Comparative Constitutionalism Project -- Working Papers (2 of 7), 1990 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Comparative Constitutionalism Project -- Working Papers (3 of 7), 1990 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Comparative Constitutionalism Project -- Working Papers (4 of 7), 1990 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Comparative Constitutionalism Project -- Working Papers (5 of 7), 1990 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Comparative Constitutionalism Project -- Working Papers (6 of 7), 1990 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Comparative Constitutionalism Project -- Working Papers (7 of 7), 1990 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Comparative Human Relations Initiative -- Southern Education Foundation -- Narrative Report, Related Memoranda, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Constitutionalism in Africa -- Reports, Program Officer Memos, Background, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Constitutionalism in Africa Conference, Abuja, Nigeria -- Program, Fact Sheet, Working Papers, Oct 5, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Consultant -- Juarez, Roberto -- Correspondence and Memoranda Re: Latino Review, Jan 30-Dec 9, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Consultant -- Tendler, Judith -- Correspondence, Memoranda Re: Government Programs Consultancy, Dec 16, 1997-Sep 18, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Cuba Meeting -- Notes, Agenda, Participants List, Mar 35-26, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - DCP Program Review -- Andean Region & Southern Cone, 1981-1990 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - DCP Program Review -- Cairo FY 1982-1996, 1981-1995 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - DCP Program Review -- Human Rights & Social Justice Program -- Rapporteur's Notes, 1982-1995 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - DCP Program Review -- Latin America & the Caribbean FY 1983-1996, 1982-1995 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - DCP Program Review -- New York-Africa FY 1982-1989, 1981-1988 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Devolution Initiative National Meeting, Birmingham, AL -- Meeting Book, Nov 17-19, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Eastern Europe -- Clinical Legal Education in the Czech Republic and Slovakia, Mar 21, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Eastern Europe -- Evaluation of FF Grant Making -- Status of Women in Russia, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Eastern Europe -- Sustainable Funding for Russian NGOs, Aug 2000 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Economic and Social Rights Learning Group -- Proposal, Memoranda and Notes on Proposed Learning Group, 1999-2000 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Evaluating Legal Services Programs -- Memoranda, Nov 2, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Ford Foundation Civil Liberties Program -- Overview of Current Interests, Nov 6, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Ford Foundation Human Rights Meeting, Benjamin Hotel, New York -- Meeting Book, Oct 25-27, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Galing Pook Foundation -- Transition Documents, Narrative Report, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Garling, Marguerite -- Transition Memo, Apr 14, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Global Law Programs Learning Initiative (GLPLI) -- Background -- Memoranda Re: Updates, Notes, Mar 23, 1998-Mar 8, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - GLPLI -- Board Presentation -- Agenda, Program, Speaking Notes, Sep 27, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - GLPLI -- Brazil Proposal -- Correspondence, May 17-Nov 17, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - GLPLI -- Case Study Plans -- Meeting Notes, Correspondence, Apr 10, 1998-Mar 29, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - GLPLI -- Correspondence from Many Roads to Justice Book Recipients, Oct 8, 1999-Oct 13, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - GLPLI -- Dissemination External Meetings -- Meeting Notes, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - GLPLI -- Dissemination Plan -- Many Roads to Justice Memoranda, Feb 29, 2000-Aug 15, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - GLPLI -- East Africa Study -- Correspondence, Notes and Background on Study of Legal Training in Africa, 2000-2001 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - GLPLI -- Indonesia -- Correspondence Re: Book Translation, Jan 25-29, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - GLPLI -- Meeting Presentation, Jun 22, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - GLPLI -- Memoranda Re: Purpose, Scope and Plan, Background, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - GLPLI -- Middle East -- Correspondence Re: Book Distribution, Nov 1, 2000-Feb 7, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - GLPLI -- Miscellaneous -- Program Description, Correspondence, Meeting Agenda, etc., 1998 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - GLPLI -- Presentation -- Memoranda Re: Staff Q&A with Meeting Information, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - GLPLI -- Rienner, Lynne -- Correspondence Re: Publication of Many Roads to Justice, Sep 24, 1999-Mar 24, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - GLPLI -- Russia -- Correspondence Re: Moscow Office Book Dissemination, Jan 22, 2000-Aug 15, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - GLPLI -- Southern Cone -- Book Dissemination Proposal, Notes, Jul-Oct 2000 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - GLPLI -- Survey -- Correspondence, Feb 11-13, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - GLPLI -- Translation -- Correspondence and Notes Re: Book Translation, Jun 19-Sep 15, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - GLPLI -- Trustee Committee Session -- Memoranda, Agenda, Background, Sep 27, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - GLPLI -- Website Memoranda and Background, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - GLPLI -- World Bank Gender Law Workshop -- Background, Nov 27-30, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - GLPLI -- Workshop on Goals Setting and Indicator Development for PSJ Program Officers -- Agenda, Workshop Materials, Feb 5, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Global HIV Initiative Learning Exchange, Pilanesburg, South Africa -- Meeting Book, Notes, Background, Apr 1, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Date Restricted Material -- Contains records less than 10 years old -- Restricted records are Open to scholarly research in 2019.
  - Global Security Learning Group -- Notes, Memoranda Summarizing Group Discussions, Aug 7, 1998-Dec 7, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Governance -- Africa Economic Research Consortium -- Evaluation, Aug 13, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Governance -- Arnold, David -- Program Papers, Jun 1985-Jan 24, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Governance -- Innovations -- Manila Meeting Memorandum Re: Galing Pook Program, Jun 16, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Governance and Civil Society Worldwide Meeting, Sao Paolo, Brazil -- Agenda, Notes, Handouts, Oct 29-Nov 2, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Grant Action List, 2006 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    Date Restricted Material -- Contains records less than 10 years old -- Restricted records are Open to scholarly research in 2017.
  - Human Rights and Social Justice -- Memorandum Re: Legal Aid Field in Middle East, DAGs, etc., Aug 7, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Human Rights Meeting -- Notes, Background, Nov 2007 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - India -- Governance Program -- Material from New Delhi Office, 1997-1998 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - International Cooperation -- South Asia Regional Security and Cooperation Program -- Current Interests, Feb 1997 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - International Relations (IR) Admin -- Background Information and Correspondence Re: FF Grantees, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - International Rescue Committee -- Meeting Notes, Background, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Joint Center for Political and Economic Studies -- Correspondence and Memoranda Re: Presidential Endowment Grant, Grant Information, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Lagos Visit -- Briefing Book, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Learning -- Articles -- Anna Kendrick Reports on FF Institutional Learning and Role of Evaluation in Forestry Work, 1985-1995 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Learning -- Background -- Memoranda Re: Transition, Grant Close-Out Evaluations, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Learning -- Memos to the Field -- Learning Group Updates (1 of 2), 1997 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Learning -- Memos to the Field -- Learning Group Updates (2 of 2), 1998-1999 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Learning -- Program Officer Ideas -- Handwritten Notes, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Learning -- Summaries/To Do -- Notes and Memoranda on PSJ Learning Groups, Jul 28, 1998-Dec 15, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Learning Enhancement Fund (LEF) -- Affirmative Action in Israel Memo, Jul 23, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - LEF -- Budgeting and Rights Mexico Meeting -- Memoranda, Jul 23-25, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - LEF -- Civil Society Consultation -- Workshops Request, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - LEF -- Colombia Initiative -- Correspondence and Memoranda Re: Peace Seminar, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - LEF -- East Africa Review of Women's Rights -- Correspondence, Nov 15, 2000-Aug 2, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - LEF -- Evaluation -- Memoranda and Notes on How to Conduct Evaluations, 1997-1999 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - LEF -- Governance in East Africa -- Correspondence Re: Study, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - LEF -- Indigenous Human Rights Training Programs -- Funds Request Memo, Apr 12, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - LEF -- International Refugee Program Review -- Correspondence, Memoranda, Dec 6, 2000-Jan 17, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - LEF -- Judicial Court Reform in China -- Review Memo, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - LEF -- Labor Mobility in China -- Review Consultancy, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - LEF -- Leadership/International Cooperation -- Funds Request, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - LEF -- Proposals -- Memoranda and Correspondence Re: Funding, Oct 28, 1999-Aug 15, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - LEF -- Study of FF Human Rights Funding -- Correspondence, Memoranda, Budget, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Learning Organization Handout -- Drafts, Notes, Correspondence, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Learning Organizations -- Notes, Background, 1997-1998 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Learning Protocol -- Cairo -- Protocol, Correspondence, Nov 23-Dec 2, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Learning Sessions -- Meeting Notes and Materials, Memorandum on PSJ Learning Mechanisms, Dec 2000 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - LOGO (Local Governance) Learning Group -- Correspondence and Memoranda Re: Workshop, Notes, 1999-2000 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Management Assistance Group -- Correspondence Re: Grant Extension, Background, 2005-2007 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Closed to scholary research.
  - NAACP -- Correspondence and Notes on Meeting, 2007 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - National Council of Churches -- Correspondence and Memoranda Re: Meeting with FF Staff, Background, Aug31-Nov 8, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Nigeria Trip -- Correspondence, Conference Information, Background Papers, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - NGO Monitor's Report -- Correspondence Re: Israel Boycott, 2007 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Nonprofit Leadership Initiative Advisory Group Meeting, Los Angeles, CA -- Meeting Notes, Background, Oct 23, 2007 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Orientation -- Grant Maker Handbook, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Date Restricted Material -- Contains records less than 10 years old -- Restricted records are Open to scholarly research in 2016.
  - Orientation -- Grant Maker Handbook, 2008 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - PSJ Field Meetings and Program Learning Groups -- Memoranda and Correspondence Re: Meetings, Mar 30-Dec 7, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - PSJ Field Statements, 1998-1999 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - PSJ Field Statements -- Human Rights, International Cooperation, Jan-Feb 1999 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - PSJ Field Statements -- Human Rights Programming, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - PSJ Organization Chart, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - PSJ Police Reform Program -- Correspondence Re: Indonesian Police Watch, Nov 14, 2000-May 9, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - PSJ Program Descriptions -- Field Statements, 2006 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - PSJ Program Orientation for Louis Ubiñas -- Initiatives, 2008 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - PSJ Program Overview and Mission Statement, Sep 15, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - PSJ Restructuring -- Memoranda, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - PSJ Staff Retreat -- Agenda, Notes, Background Memos, Jan 1997 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - PSJ Staff Retreat -- Portfolio Descriptions (1 of 2), Jan 1997 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - PSJ Staff Retreat -- Budgets (2 of 2), Jan 1997 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - PSJ Staff Retreat -- Notes, Correspondence, Agenda, Background, Nov 1997 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - PSJ Worldwide Meeting -- Background Conversations -- Correspondence Re: Agenda Planning, Arranging a Speaker, Jan 3-Apr 30, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - PSJ Worldwide Meeting -- Discussions on Proposed Agenda, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - PSJ Worldwide Meeting -- Notes, Memoranda, Follow Up, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - PSJ Worldwide Meeting -- Preparations -- Speech, Outline, PowerPoint, Jun 20, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - PSJ Worldwide Meeting, Krakow, Poland -- Meeting Book (1 of 2), Jun 4-9, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - PSJ Worldwide Meeting, Krakow, Poland -- Meeting Book (2 of 2), Jun 4-9, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Peace, Equity and Governance Cluster -- Structured Staffing -- Memoranda Re: Reorganization, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Police -- Articles -- Reports on Meetings, Memoranda Re: Articles, Reference, 1997-1998 (Box 14, Folder 1)